Now that we have our car icon component let's start building our car dropdown.
So if we look at our dropdown we know that there is a container.
There is this section with items inside that a scroll level.
And there's also a go to checkout button and it opens and is seemingly stuck to that area just underneath
our cart icon.
So let's start building this component.
The first thing we're going to do is we are going to create a cart component here.
We'll just call it cart and inside of it actually let's call it cart dropdown.
It's a bit more direct about what it is.
So we're going to create our cart dropdown component Dutch assets as well as our cart dropdown dot styles
DOT says we are gonna import react from react.
And we're also going to import in our custom button because we know we need one at the very end
or import in our style sheet and what we're going to use for our component is a regular stateless component
and inside will be a containing do with the class name of cart dropdown and also this div that has the
class name of our cart items because this will be the thing that contains our cart items which will
keep empty for now and then our custom button
and we will say go to checkout on the inside and here we will export t fault our cart dropdown cart
dropped it.
Now let's bring in our style sheet so I have the styles here for you as well for this component and
I'm pushing the margin top of auto for our button so that it's always at the bottom.
The car items takes up 240 pixels it aligns everything inside so that it flows vertically and it has
an oversight flow of scroll but we won't create car items just yet.
We have to bring our cart dropdown into our header component and we got to import in our cart dropdown
component
cart dropdown cart dropdown component and we're going to place it just outside of our options div because
we want it to sit just outside of that div.
So now if we go back to our application we'll see it right there awesome.
OK now what we have to do is conditionally show or hide this card dropdown and to do so we are going
to trigger something that will show or hide this component based off of some true or false value.
Now we are going to create a cart reducer to do this and we're going to set the value of some property
probably called Hidden on that reducer based on clicking this icon because maybe there are other ways
that we want to hide this in the future we don't know but what we do want to do is we want to keep that
in our global state in case anywhere else wants to trigger the ability to hide or show our dropdown.
So let's implement that.