So now that we have our car icon component and our cart dropdown component we have to figure out how
to trigger our cart dropdown to hide and show based off clicking the cart icon.
Now you might be wondering if we could just find that functionality into our head our component because
both these components are here and using our local component state we could possibly add an on click
handler here that updates a state value on our header that sets it to true or false.
And then based off of that true false value we just hide or show this car dropdown.
And that would be entirely valid if we were certain that the only way we wanted to hide or show our
car dropdown was within our head our component.
But because we are not sure of that.
Perhaps we want to show or hide our car dropdown in another component.
We want to move that functionality and that capability outside of the header component and inside of
our global redux state.
Now how do we do that.
Well first let's create the redux files and they'll look very similar to our user files.
So instead of user or call it cart we'll make a cart.
Actions that J us a cart dot reducer dodgy us and a cart dot type stuff.
J ust now starting with our reducer we know that we need an initial state
where the hidden value is true because we want to hide our dropdown when they first comes to our Web
site then we're going to have our cart reducer equal to a function where state is equal to our initial
state.
If no value comes in.
So default value of initial state and then our action and using a switch statement on the action date
type we will now selectively render with a case of let's say toggle cart hidden.
The reason why we want to use a toggle versus a set is because our cart component will either be in
a true or false state.
So it's either hidden or not hidden right.
And we know that we're mainly switching it back and forth between true and false.
So instead of passing in a value for our actions our payload what we can actually do is we can say hidden
is equal to state to hit it.
So that exclamation mark is saying that whatever this boolean value is I want you to convert it to the
opposite of it.
Right.
So if it's true or to be false if it's false I want it to be true and then by default we want to return
just the state.
Now this of course is a string but we want to make an action type for it.
So let's go to our car dot actions and let's export default
heart action types where toggle card hidden goes to the string toggle car hidden.
And now we just need to import that from our car types
and it will be cart action types
toggle card hidden and we'll export out our reducer as the default.
So now we have our code
oh maybe I got to move this down here sometimes our lender yells at us now to make the actual oh wait
i move it.
Oh sorry I put this in the wrong file cart types my that wrong file that all that that's definitely
confusing the file the file naming conventions.
It's a thing that always used to throw me off when I was first learning read.
OK.
So definitely don't feel bad because we all make these mistakes.
Now the cart action we actually need to make the action now.
So let's import in our car action types from car types and what our value will be.
We will set it as X export concert toggle cart.
Hidden is equal to a function.
And we're not going to pass a payload because we don't need one.
We're just going to set type equal to cart action types.
Dot toggle cart hit in payload is actually an optional property on our action object and inside of a
reducer we're not actually using the payload inside of this respective case.
Right.
So there's no need for us to pass a payload.
We just need to know that if it's of this type we're just going to switch it from whatever its previous
state was to its opposite state and now inside of cart icon.
Let's find that action here so let's import connect from react redux.
Let's bring in our action type
part action.
Toggle car hit an and we need our map dispatch to props which gets a dispatch and we're gonna call it
toggle cart hidden will just be a function that triggers the dispatch of toggle cart hit.
And now we'll pass this into our connect function.
Passing know as the default so now we'll be able to access toggle cart hit in here and we can just find
it on click like so and now if we look we'll see that we fire the action now of course our state is
updating oh we actually have to add our cart reducer to our route reducer so that's a step that we always
got to remember so cart reducer from our cart cart producer.
This is another common mistake that we make when we first start using redux as well as that we'll forget
to port and add our cart to our cart reducer.
So now if we look we'll see that our cart by default is hit and true if we click it we'll see that now
it's false.
So now we just have to hide and show this dropdown based off of that value.
So let's go back to our header component and we'll impart in O where we have our maps data props.
So what we need to do structure off of our state is also now the cart and then the hidden value.
So I'm actually going to show you more advanced way to D structure as well so off of our state we want
the user and off the user we want the current user.
So this is the syntax you write when you want to d structure nested values.
Right.
So by going colon and then another D structure bracket we're saying I want you to give me this value
off of the user which is being destructor off of the state.
So similarly we will do that off of the cart and we want to hit in value and then instead of this we
can now just do that and now pull the hidden value off and we can just selectively render this based
off of a ternary operator.
So if it's hidden if it is true then I want to render nothing but if it's not then render the cart dropdown
component.
And now if we look we can see that we can toggle our dropdown now before we add our add item feature
to our cart and to our application let's commit our code.
We know that what we are adding is our cart icon added cart icon and cart dropdown components to our
application also implemented heart reducer
and then let's push and continue with our had item.