What we're going to tackle now is grouping the cart items inside of our cart reducer.
So if I add this item four times what we will have is the same for items inside of our car.
Items array which we don't want.
We want to instead just add some quantity property to this object and increase or decrease it based
on whether or not we add the same item or we want to remove the same item from our cart.
Now how do we tackle this.
Well we're going to write a utility function for this and there's actually many ways to handle this
but I'm going to write the way that best obeys relax rules the rule being that when ever we make this
update we always want to return a new array even if the object stays the same.
And we're just increasing the property because in order for change detection to trigger we have to remember
that if the object that is being used as a property to display stays the same and simply a property
changes react will not re render the component.
So we need to make sure that every time we pass in a new object with an increase in that quantity value
so let's actually write this code.
So the first thing we're going to do is we are going to know that we need to call that function that
we're about to write on our reduce code and we are going to make it inside of a new file called cart
dot utilize dot J S inside of here.
We can add any utility functions related to our cart redux code so what I'm going to write is first
this function called add item to cart which is gonna take two arguments.
The first is all the existing cart items that are in our cart items array right now and then the second
item is going to be the cart item that we want to add because what we are gonna do is we're going to
look inside of our existing cart items to see if that cart item already exists and we are going to actually
write that in this code.
So we're gonna set it to the value of existing cart item.
If cart items stuff find is true and cart items defined we'll return you the first item found in our
array based off a condition that we pass in here and the condition is based off of this function where
we get each individual cart item and we'll check the car items I.D. if it matches the cart item we're
trying to add I.D.
if it matches it we'll set that cart item where this condition is true to our constant.
If it doesn't find anything after looping through all of it it will be undefined.
So then we're going to check well if existing cart item exists then what we're going to return from
our entire function is our car item stop map because car times not map will return us a new array and
we remember that we need to return new versions of our state so that our components know to re render
properly now what we're going to pass is cart item right inside of our dot map.
So again each car item and we will do the same thing where if cart item to I.D. is equal to our car
item to add dot idea then we will create a new object where we have the cart item except the quantity
will be cart item quantity plus one.
Now we don't have a quantity yet but we're going to solve that after.
So first what we'll do is if that item doesn't match.
We just want to return the original car item because there's no need to update any of the components
that might be relying on our object.
All right so we don't need to make any modifications.
We'll just return the item as it is now.
If the car item is not found inside of our array then we want to return a new array with all of our
existing car items that were already there.
But we also want to now add in an object which is equal to our cart item to add except we're gonna give
it a base quantity of one.
And this way whenever we add our car items in any subsequent cart items we'll be able to reference that
quantity value that we have added to our objects when we store them.
And now we just have to import this into our reducer
from cart utilize and it is called add item to cart.
And now we just have to replace this code with our add item to cart passing in our state dog cart items
as well as our action payload which is the item that we want to add and now we actually need to make
one more modification.
So in our shop data code I accidentally set it so that the I.D. of the items actually repeat.
So even though they're unique in their respective array so I was going to raise reference the same I.D.
and based on the code we wrote this will cause a problem because it'll say that Brown brim is actually
the same idea as Adidas NMD.
So I've provided a new file with the updated simply so that the ideas are all unique on the items themselves.
So you just need to replace this array with the new Array that I gave you
and now we save that and if we check our code we'll see that.
Let's say I add this brown brim hat we look inside of our cart items and there is our object except
with the one quantity.
But if I add it two more times if we look in our cart we'll see that our objects quantity value has
increased.
Which is exactly what we want to do.
We are grouping our items together based on this quantity value and what we're also now able to do is
if we need to create some kind of remove action we can easily do so because we have this quantity value
as well so before we go on and build the actual cart component that displays the items inside of our
cart dropdown let's commit our code so let's just check and we have some pretty simple stuff so we'll
just say updated shop data with new data and then updated cart utilize to group items in cart reducer
we'll push this up
and let's move on.