OK now let's create our cart item component.
Now we know that the items that our cart item components will be getting will be the same item as the
one that we display in our collection items because in our collection items we get an image url.
We get the price we get the name and then we also now know we'll get a quantity.
Because we'll be pulling that item off from our state.
So what we're gonna do keeping in mind these properties is first we're going to make our component so
we'll make a cart item component and create our usual files our cart item component digests X and our
cart item styles does SOF and inside of our car item component we need our react from react and we'll
also need our cart item styles and now what we're going to set as our car item will be a functional
component where we'll d structure off those properties that we need from our item but we'll probably
pass the whole item through so we're gonna get the item and off of it we want the image URL we want
the price and we also want the name
and what we'll do is we will return a div with the class name of cart item.
We're also going to need an image where the source points to our image euro and for the old key we'll
just say that it's an item and then inside of our div we can say this thing is our item details container
because looking at the actual component on the left side is our image but on the right side is our details
so here we're gonna have a span with the class name of name or we'll display the name
and then we'll have the same thing except for price where we'll have the price
with our dollar sign and now let's export this as the default
and we'll also need our quantity which we know will also get
the structure that off and we can just explicitly say quantity times this amount.
So now if we look at our cart item styles I have also provided for you the styling here and now we just
need to import the car item into our cart component cart dropdown so let's import in our new cart item
and in our cart dropdown we need to display it inside of this div but we need access to those cart items.
So what we're gonna do is we're going to pull them off using connect off of our retail store
and what we will write is our maps date to props
equals are function where we get state and what little return is carte items which will go to state
actually.
Let's just d structure it off state.
So we need cart and then off cart.
We need cart items and we can just have it horse cart items like this.
What connect with our map stage props and now we'll d structure our cart items here.
And inside of our car items we can map out our cart items.
So cart items that map but the cart.
Item and we will render our car item component where the key goes to our cart.
Item I.D. and item is the cart.
Item
got to be careful that casing okay.
And now if we look at our actual code we open up our component.
And if we add our item there it is we're able to now add as many items as we want and we have them displayed
here.
So in a similar way once we make our checkout page it'll be pretty much the same thing.
We add the items we'll pull them into the component and we'll display them this pattern.
Now we've seen a couple of times now is hopefully very very easy to write.
You can see that once you get used to writing the code in the reduced hours there's not much complexity
when it comes to how to separate out your code that's kind of the amazing thing about redux is that
it just follows our unit directional data flow pattern that we need and we need to think about when
writing our real code.
We have these actions that trigger state changes and then using that state we pull them into our components
and then we display the respective elements that we need so we will do this a couple more times but
hopefully by now you can see the benefit of what redux does for us and this pattern.
OK so now that we have our card dropdown let's commit our code Stannis and get commit created cart item
component and connected our cart dropdown
cart items reducer
awesome.
Now let's continue.