Welcome back.
React is simply a group of components that are rendered in a tree like structure.
So this would be the app dodgy yes and each one of these components would have state for example the
red dots over here.
They have state so for example this app component will have a state of signed in AZ.
And let's say the state is user in that case this user component might have a state of user Mitch or
if signed in as is admin it might render the admin component and any anytime you see the blue dot.
That means there was a change.
So if there's a change here it can update something into this component and we render and we did this
in react so again with a simple react app we can have nice views and maybe have different states and
different components but eventually as our app gets bigger we end up with something like this where
we have more and more components more and more state within that component.
Or we can have one massive state at the very top here which also gets pretty hard and all these blue
dots as they update they also have to update the state and then we render and this example over here
is just a little diagram but you can see with all these arrows how confusing it's going to get and keeping
track of all this state is really really hard.
So we need some form of a state management and Redux solve this problem for us.
How could we make this diagram simpler and make things easier to understand in our heads as developers
redux came up with a novel concept.
What if we just remove all the state so this dot state from all the components.
What if we just have props so all these components just have props being passed down and now the state
we keep it in a store and a store is simply just the state which is this dot state that react had but
in one massive object just like you see here.
So one single object that describes how our app should look and all we do is just pass down that state
to whichever component needs it as props so our diagram from looking like this with just react can go
to looking like this with redux where none of the components need to hold state anymore and we can have
one massive object that describes our entire app and whichever component needs that prop can just be
passed down to it.
And any updates that happen go through the state the state game gets modified and then we pass down
that information to the component this diagram might be confusing without actually coding anything and
we'll come back to it.
So this makes sense but even just visual you can see that this diagram looks a lot simpler than the
diagram before it.
We have a lot less arrows and everything just flows nicer so as we go through the videos you're gonna
get more and more familiar with this idea of state management.
But I want you to keep in mind that that is what redux is solving redux is a library that makes state
management easier not only for react but for any tools that we use.
It just happens to work really really well with.
And redux actually got inspiration from database design from things such as events sourcing or CQ RSS
which you can read up more on databases had the same problem.
All these updates and all these changes happened but we needed a way to make sure that all these changes
are organized in a nice cohesive way.
All right let's get into the next video and get a little bit deeper with redux.
By.