OK so now that we have our cart as well as our ability display cart items we want to tackle something
like displaying the number of items we have in our cart inside of our cart icon.
Because right now it just displays zero well thinking about what we know already about pulling redux
state into local components.
Maybe we do something where we would write a map state to props where we would pull the state in and
then get the value.
Now what would this look like.
Well we would write our map states of props value and here we would get our state where we would destruction
if cart and from cart we'd pull off the cart items and maybe we'd pass in the value of item count which
is equal to accumulating the quantity on each of our cart items.
Now if we were to look at our code of what our state looks like and let's look at the items themselves
we know that the quantity value is a number and we want to add them all together to get the total number
of items we have.
Well this is a good time to use our reduce function if we remember where we want to bring it down to
one final value.
So what we could call is something like cart items reduce where we would pass and 0 as the initial accumulator
value.
Because if you remember we want to add all of the values in our quantity so we would get our accumulated
quantity as the first argument in our first function and then we would get the actual cart item as the
second argument.
And what we would return is accumulated quantity plus cart item quantity and what this will do for us
is it will accumulate all the number values of the quantities on all the cart items.
Now if you remember from our reducer lesson how we added up those values together this is doing the
exact same thing but using our quantity value.
So if we can imagine we had three card items and the quantities were 1 2 3 respectively while the first
time our reducer code gets called it will add 0 and 1 giving us 1 then one plus two giving us three
then three plus three giving us six.
And we would end up with an item count of six.
So what this will do then is pass that six in as our item count parameter which we would then pass in
as a prop to our component so we then D structure it off of our props and pass it in place of 0.
And now if we save and we look at our app we'll see that our account goes up for every item that we
add and we'll see that it matches.
We have two two and one which gives us five total quantity of items.
Now what we've written just now is called a selector because what we're doing here is we are writing
some kind of code that gets a state as in the whole state object and then pulls off just a small portion
or a slice of that state because what we're getting is we're getting the cart then the cart items and
then reducing over those cart items that get a new value.
We're computing out a new value based off of the state.
Now the caveat to this even though this is how redux suggests the code to be written is that we'll notice
that when ever any reducer updates when we remember looking at our reduced code we're always returning
a new object.
Now whenever we return a new object and Redux re composes and rebuilds the entire state object map states
of props is actually getting called every single time which is always passing in new props to our components.
And why this is important is because this is always re rendering R components.
Now I can actually show you how this will happen.
Let's say for example we console log whenever a map states of props gets called and I'll say I am being
called so even though our car icon component only cares about card items what ends up happening is whenever
we change the state.
So let's say for example we're not modifying our cart state let alone our cart item state.
We're modifying our current user on our user state.
If I sign in right now you'll see that I am being called gets triggered because the map states of props
inside of our cart icon component is still being called and then if I sign out right again it's just
use our current user getting changed and but again our console log is still firing which means that
our map states of props keeps firing.
And this is important because our reduce is always returning a new value because reduce doesn't know
that the car items coming in might be the exact same.
So let's say we have two items in our cart and it reduces down to the value of two if these car items
come in again.
But it's the exact same two items reduce is still getting called so we're still always getting a new
computed value and you might be thinking why would that happen if the objects are the same well they're
actually not because our state is always a new object which means that everything even if the value
is identical the object of our total state is a brand new object which means everything inside of it
all of the data inside of it is brand new and that's why every time reduced gets called whatever those
crimes will be will also be brand new.
Even if the value is the same two car items.
Now this is not good for performance because we don't want to re render our component every time the
state changes especially if those state changes don't actually modify the parts of the state that our
component cares about.
So what we would want to do is to be able to store or cache the value of what our selector is using
to compute its value.
So if the car item values don't actually change right and if the output of the selector doesn't change
we don't want to re render our component.
Well what this is actually called is memorization which is the caching of the selectors value and we
can actually achieve this kind of memorization using a library called Re select and re select allows
us to write these selectors in such a way so that it knows that if the properties that it's pulling
from the state and using are the same in the sense that their value hasn't changed and the output of
the selector is not different then it won't actually pass them into our component it'll just pass the
old value and R react component will know not to re render.
There's also other benefits in the sense that it allows us to actually separate our selectors and make
them reusable.
Now let's actually take a look at how to do this.