The first thing we have to do is bring in the result like the library.
So inside of our terminal let's add re select to our node modules now in order for us to use re select
and write these selector code.
We have to switch up our folder structure a little bit because we are going to move the code that we
normally write inside of our map state to props into their own folder inside of the respective redux
folder.
That this will be related to.
So for example this car item count might be a reusable selector in the sense that we might want an item
count in multiple places of our application and error for us to do that.
We would add it into a new file called cart dot selectors dot J.S..
Now what we want to import from re select is this function called Create selector
but before we use it there's actually a couple things that we need to think about so there's actually
two types of selectors we can write the first type is called an input selector that doesn't use create
selector and then the second type is called an output selector that does use input selectors and creates
selector to build themselves.
Now I'll show you both but let's start with the first one which is an input selector all an input selector
is is it is a function that usually takes this naming structure of select let's say cart for example
and what it does is it's a function that gets the whole state and just returns a slice of it one layer
DB usually.
So for us we just want the cart.
So we're going to pull state dog cart because what it's going to get is the whole reducer state and
we just want this piece of it using this input selector of select cart.
Now the reason we need this input selector is because this next selector we're going to build is going
to actually use create selector.
So we're gonna say export concept select cart items which is a property on our cart and how it's going
to look is it's going to be our create selector call and what it takes is actually two arguments.
The first argument is a collection so an array of input selectors.
So we're gonna say select cart and then the second argument is going to be a function that will return
the value we want out of the selector.
And what we're going to get in its parameters is actually each output of the input selectors in the
array but in the order that those selectors were written.
So for example if we had another selector say const select user equals state.
Right.
And we just take state DOT user.
If we were to pass this in like so right the arguments that we would see would be cast and then user
and then whatever we output will be the output of the selector but because we don't need the select
user we're just going to use our select cart inputs selector.
So our function takes this form or we get cart and what we'll return is cart dog cart items and because
we use create selector to make this select cart item selector it's now a memoir selector.
Now why is this important.
Well let's actually make our car items count selector as well that we'll use in our cart icon.
Let's copy this.
Cart items reduce over.
So let's make a new selector called Select cart items count and it'll be another create selector except
what we're gonna pass in can also be are select cart items.
Right.
It doesn't have to be just starting from our input selectors but input selectors are just selectors
that only return a piece of the state.
It's very rare that we actually end up using such a large piece of state in our actual components.
We always use these smaller more specific selectors that have some kind of transform them.
So for example let's say our select car items count takes select cart items so that we get our car items
here.
And what will output is the reduced call on those card items.
So this gives us back the total quantity of all the card items.
Well let's pull that into our car icons component and see how it works.
So we'll import in from redux cart cart selectors and now if we replace this code with our selector
call but we stop the pass of the state right so let's pass Dayton and what's happening is that we're
passing our whole reducer state into the selector which then goes OK I need to reference select card
items which references select card.
So it passes the state in here.
It gets the car object which gets passed into this function which passes out the card items which are
select card items count because it's relying on the selector passes the card items into this function
which finally reduces over and gives us our actual final card items count which we then pass in as item
count as a prop into our cart icon component Wow that's a lot of words.
So now if we check our application we'll see that our code still works the exact same way but now we
have a memorized selector for this value.
OK now we can actually replace our other component that uses our card items with the selector.
So the other item that we use that uses our new Select card item selector is our cart dropdown component
and here we're just going to replace this card items with our selector and what we can do is import
it in
redux cart cart item selector so it'll be select cart items and now instead of restructuring we want
the whole state so that we can pass it in like so and this will make sure that our cart dropdown component
is not getting re rendered when ever the state changes that's unrelated to the card items.
So if we sign out our cart items in our cart dropdown as well as our car items count is not changing
and therefore our cart dropdown and our car icon component do not need to re render which helps save
us on performance and we will write a whole lot more selectors as we've built this application.
But now we have managed to help save some re renders off of our components.
Now let's commit our code and say updating our application with re select replaced cart selectors with
memorised selectors and let's push and proceed with our lessons.