Now that we have our cart selectors let's actually convert our user map state to props selectors to
also use re select so let's make a new user dot selector digest and let's actually look at what we're
pulling on if I remember correctly our header component uses it and all it gets is the current user
so at this point it might as well just be worth it for us to memorize the selectors using both a hidden
selector as well for cart and our current user selector for our user so we'll import in our create selector
from re select and we're just going to get our state selector select the user equal state which for
sure is state DOT user and then export const select current user equals create selector and as you remember
the first argument can be either an array of our input selectors and then our last argument being the
function that gets the return of this input selector.
So our user reducer and then we'll return user to current user.
Now another thing is actually let's say we imagine we had another selector like say we wanted to also
pull off our hidden right.
So we had a select cart and then let's say we needed the cart hit in value with our user value for some
reason right.
I don't really know but you can imagine where we would come up with a case where we might want to use
multiple inputs selectors and as we know from our last example we would get cart like this where we
would be able to use it in some kind of way.
But there's another way that you can actually structure your create selector where instead of passing
in an array you just pass it in as arguments in successive order the function in the animal still remain
the same.
So you can either pass all of your inputs selectors in in the order that you want them to appear what
their outputs inside of are function parameters or we can just pass them in as an array.
It really makes no difference.
Personally I like to use the array but it doesn't really matter.
So let's get rid of this because we don't need it.
So now we have our current user let's also make the one for r hidden and we'll just export contest select
cart hidden equals create selector with our select cart selector and then we'll just return cart Doc
cart hidden part Doc cart hidden.
OK and now let's start replacing the components we have with the respective selectors
we'll import also in another thing called create structured selector from re select and I'll show you
what that does in a second once we bring in our respective selectors
and we want select cart hidden and we also want select current user
select current user so how we've seen this done before was where we would pass in our state into our
selectors right.
So let's say we want a current user.
Well we would take the whole state and then say current user points to our select current user.
And then we pass the state of now we know that for hidden it's pretty much the same thing we will call
a select card hidden and then pass in the state.
But if we have five six selectors or pretty much just doing the exact same thing five six times.
Right.
So what we can actually do is use our create structured selector call
and instead of passing it as a function we just pass it like so where the properties that we want point
to the correct selector and then create structure selector will automatically pass are top level state
that we get as our map states props into each subsequent selector and now if we look at our head our
component we'll see that our code should remain the same.
We still get our current user inside of our state and it's being passed in
and we are card hidden and still works as usual.
Now let's see where else we have any map states of props being called objects.
We can do this here to
import in
from redux.
User selectors select current user
now even though we only have one selected property that we're passing into our maps it's props.
We should still use create structured selector because if in the future we do need to pull in more then
it's easy because we've already converted our code over to using create structured selector
and the main benefit of using it is just that it extends us a little bit less code rewrite than we would
normally have to do
select current user.
Now let's actually use create structure selector and all of our other components like our card dropdown
so we've got to import our create structured selector and then we can just replace this part of our
code and take out the state and then the last one is I believe cart icon.
Yes
and then same thing
OK.
And now if we look our code still all works the same but now we are able to memorize all of our selector.
OK so moving forward now all of our code is going to be written with re select regarding our selectors
and this is actually the most common practice when using redux inside of a react application while also
using re select.