Now what we need to build next is our checkout page.
We have to start styling it and also creating the checkout items.
Now looking at the final products for our checkout page we see that there will be a total some checkout
items.
This header as well as this section here that has to do with payment with stripe.
Now we'll take this one part of the time and let's actually build our base page first.
So let's have this total and then let's have this header as well as the checkout items which we'll tackle
after.
So let's just first build the checkout page.
Now what we know that we need from the checkout page will be the header first.
So let's just build that out now.
I already have the styles for you but we'll explore a little bit after we set up the base HD Himmel
elements for this.
We need a class name of checkout page and inside of our checkout page will be our checkout header
so it will just be a div that hold some of these block like elements together and these block elements
are called header blocks
and inside of them is a span that has some text regarding what it will say and it will be respectively.
Product Description Quantity Price and remove.
So let's copy this over actually four more times for each block and this one will say Product
Description
Oh sorry.
This is quantity
and finally remove
for the actual styling.
I have them as normal so you can just paste them into your style sheet.
And let's take a quick look at what we're doing here.
The main thing to focus on is that our checkout header is 100 percent of the page and the page itself
is fifty five percent of the total that is available to it.
So for us that's why it's centered in this quantity amount and it's responsive accordingly but each
header block inside of our header is twenty three percent of the total width except for the last child
which is our last header block which is 8 percent so twenty three times four is ninety two plus eight
gives us a hundred and the reason for this is because our remove only holds the X button so it doesn't
need as much space as the other header blocks inside of our header.
But now that we have our header component let's actually bring in our cart items from our state and
then we'll build our checkout item and finish this page.
So let's just first bring in all the things that we need.
So we need connect from reactor redux.
We also need create structured selector from re selected because we know we're gonna be pulling some
stuff off the state and then we're going to bring in our actual select cart items from redux
parts selectors and we'll pull off select cart items
now let's write our map states props maps state props which will be our create structured selector and
we'll pass it in as carte items GOES TO SELECT CARD items now as far as the total goes.
We need another selector for it that will add all of the price of our items together that selector.
We will add to our cart selector and we'll say we'll call it expert contest select cart total.
Yeah like our total.
That sounds pretty good.
And what we'll need is we'll need all of our car items and it's going to be very similar to our reduce
the previous one we had four items count.
The only difference is that we're going to be accumulating the value of the price of the card at a plot
price times the item quantity so we can actually copy this over and just modify it so
because the main thing we're trying to get is the total cost right.
And we know the cost of each item and we know how many of each item we have.
So it's pretty much just going to be the quantity multiplied by the price.
So now let's bring this into our component
and then we'll say the total value is this and then let's connect it together and we'll add our maps
stage props
and then D structure off both the car items that were passing in now as well as the total
and now what we can do right after our header component is we can put a quick little map right of our
car items
and we'll just show the name for now before we build our component.
But let's just make sure that the parts that we can control for now are working and we just want to
render a car item Donny and then after this we're gonna have a div that has the class name of total
and inside will be the span
that has our total and now we save and if we look we'll see that because we have no items right.
Our total is zero but once we add our items in
we'll see that our total is updating and there's the name of our items cool.
So nothing new nothing really that different from what we've done so far but now we have our checkout
page.
So let's build our checkout item.