Hello It's Andre here again.
I want you to notice what e whore has been doing so far and he's going to continue to do throughout
the course that is he's writing extensible code.
Are you starting to feel like we're doing a lot of things over and over the same way we're creating
reduced hours and actions and selectors and connecting components and rendering components and if things
seem repetitive to you.
That's actually a good thing because what we're doing is we're making things very simple now we're creating
a lot of files in our project but these files are all usually under one hundred lines of code each file
is very very simple isn't it.
We haven't been any crazy long thousand line algorithms.
Everything is nice small and simple.
And if you notice each one makes each component very very small and also very extensible that is he
reuses components and features across the application so that he's not constantly doing the same thing
over and over it's OK if we're copying code that is well similar in let's say a selector or using map
state to props over and over.
The idea is that he's structured the project in such a way that your eye could come to the project and
really easily add features really easily add a custom button or a cart item.
And this is a sign of a really good developer because when he's coding He's coding for the future as
well.
He knows that by thinking a little bit about how to make the code more extensible in the future he'll
benefit as he takes on more and more features because he can use the same functionality in one part
of the app in another part of the app and react and Redux really allows us to create extensible code
and the other word that you might be thinking of is also predictable code.
There's nothing hard about what we're doing right now.
Everything is super easy and predictable at least it is once you get used to the react redux syntax.
But at the end of the day we're just creating really declarative code really predictable pure functions
that can be extended so keep an eye on that throughout the course because this is why you want to do.
You don't want to make code that makes you look impressive or clever or tough you want code so simple
that anybody can read it let's keep going.