Before we build our checkout item we can actually make a small tweak to our Web site to make it more
of a flowing user experience.
Now in order for us to go to our checkout page we have to open up our cart dropdown and then click the
go to checkout button.
But once we get to this page our dropdown still open but we know that will end up displaying the same
information to our user because the car items will be reflected in the checkout items and that just
seems like a lot of redundancy.
So what we can do is actually trigger a toggle whenever we click our go to checkout to toggle the hidden
state of our cart because we know that in order for our user to access to go to checkout button the
hidden state must be false because our dropdown is open.
So we know that if we were to call our toggle there we're not going to get any unexpected behavior where
we don't know the state of what our hidden is again because we know that dropdown must be open for them
to have triggered the go to checkout button click.
So what can we do in order to do this.
Well we can just simply bring in our toggle hit and action into our cart dropdown component from redux
cart cart actions and we'll bring in toggle cart hidden.
Now the way that we're used to doing this inside our Kinect would be to write our map dispatch the props
and then pass in a dispatched call of our action creator of toggle cart hit it now what we might not
know is that connect actually passes dispatch into our components as a prop if we do not supply a second
argument to connect.
So if we don't supply map dispatch the props as the second parameter Connect will pass the dispatch
into our dropdown.
So our component as a property and the reason it does this is because if we need to make one off action
dispatches Well there's no reason to write another map dispatch to props it might be more verbose so
we can actually see this if we for example log out all the other props that we have access to.
So just to demonstrate this let's just return and then console log all the other props that were knocked
structuring so everything other than car items and history and now we'll see when we open that this
is what we have we do have access to this dispatch.
So what's great about that is that now instead of writing an unnecessary additional map dispatch the
props we can just bring in dispatch like so expand our on click function using a multi line.
Right.
Which are the squiggles and then adding another dispatch passing in our toggle cart hit an action creator.
And now if we save we'll see that if we go to our checkout our Togo card hidden action is being fired.
So now that we have this improved user flow let's build out our checkout item.