Now let's build our checkout item component.
Now our checkout item component is going to use the cart items that we have stored in our state.
Very similar to how we pull them into our cart dropdown.
We're going to pull them into our checkout page and then populate that dropdown or not dropdown but
that list of checkout items that we see in our final.
So let's actually build this component.
Now let's go into our application go to our checkout page
and right here is where we're going to map out our checkout item.
So let's build the component.
Let's go to our component folder and make a new one called checkout item and inside we need our usual
checkout item dock component ASX as well as our styles page checkout item dot styles dot SAS.
Now inside of our component we've got to impart react from our act and import in our style sheet.
Now as usual I've included the style sheet for you under your resources and you're just gonna copy it
and put it inside of your style sheet.
Now the main thing to note is that the width of these three categories is the same as the width of the
three headers or the four headers that we have.
The only difference is that there is a container for the actual image and the image itself sits inside.
And we'll see what that looks like in terms of how we're laying it out in the H2 out but that's how
we're able to align them together.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna declare our contents checkout item and it's gonna be a functional
component that returns this div with the class name of checkout item and then inside we're gonna have
that image container.
I was telling you about.
Which will just be a div but the class name of image container and then inside of that we're gonna have
our image.
Now the reason why we use a container for our image is because it's easier for us to control the size
of this section that holds our image.
We can throw some padding on it right and then give it that width and then to have our image inside
be constrained by it and by constraint I just mean that we set the width and height based off of what
the size of this container is and we can apply the padding here without having to affect the other sections
because maybe we don't want the same kind of padding on those.
It's just easier to put the image that we have inside of this container.
Now we're going to provide the old key of item and this is just for those screenwriters because when
people who have disabilities that use a screenwriter for the browser whenever they had an image they
can actually see the image.
So they get read out what that description will be.
And for us it will just be item it just easier for us to say if they know that it's an image then they
know item by the point that they actually use the screen or read it they know the item name so they
don't really need to have a full understanding perhaps of what the image will be next we're going to
add our spans and here's where we're going to use name and then let's just repeat this for the respective
Quantity Price and then the last one.
This will not be a span site.
It will actually be a div because this is what's going to hold our Remove button now our Remove button
is going to be a UTF 8 winging.
Now you can actually find a good list of them right here at this W3 schools link that I'm gonna put
on your screen right now.
Now what UTF 8 is essentially a standard that most browsers have that represents what characters they're
able to display or they're able to recognize.
Right.
So all the letters that we type that we're most familiar with those all fall into the UTF 8 categorization.
But there are also these other additional symbols that we can render right that our browser knows what
they represent.
And we're just going to use this X for r x and the reason for it is because it's more balanced right.
It's essentially like an icon that our browser is naturally aware of so in order for us to use it we
can just copy this text right.
In fact if you had Try it you'll see where it's demonstrated.
We have to apply this Ampersand hashtag before we actually use the number.
And then we've got to put a semicolon right and that's that same number.
So inside of here we're just going to put this here and then we're actually going to pass on our problems.
Now we know that we're going to use the card items that we have in our store but we're also going to
pass on the full item and the reason why we want to pass on the full item rather than spread the props
into our components as we would any other way is because we know that we eventually want to increase
and decrease this quantity as well as hit the remove to remove all of the items that are in the store
regarding this card item now.
Passing the full item is mandatory because we know with our cart items when we wrote our card action
an item we needed the whole item in order for it to work.
So if we want to toggle and increase the quantity we're pretty much just firing our add item call.
But this time we also want it to be done inside of this component.
So we just gotta follow the same requirements as are ad item.
Action creator so inside of a checkout item we're just going to make sure to pass the whole item as
a prop as well.
But we can just structure off the other values that we need in order to apply them into the component.
So we're gonna need name.
We're gonna need image you're all we're gonna need price.
Now we're gonna need quantity now.
Now that we have our values inside of our image we're just going to set the sauce equal to the image
you are.
As for the name we're just gonna render the name.
Same thing with quantity and price
and then let's just export this out
as the default
and bring it into our checkout page component
and here we'll just import it in
checkout item checkout item component and then instead of rendering this item name we'll just render
out our cart our checkout item and pass cart item in as a prop
we'll also make sure to set our key equal to our car.
Item I.D. Now if we save go back to our application add some items and go to our checkout We'll see
that we have our component now before we continue with building in the remove feature as well as decreasing
and increasing the quantity.
Let's just commit our code.
So let's go back to our terminal and let's check what we've added so we've done our checkout page and
we'll say added checkout page checkout item component and updated cart to use selectors from re select
and now let's push it up
and build our checkout item functionality.