Now in the last lesson we created our Remove button with our X icon winking.
Now we actually need to create the functionality in our redux code in order to clear this item out now.
This is actually going to be very similar to what we did from a redux standpoint.
As far as when we added items and you can imagine it must be similar because what we're doing is we're
trying to update our cart items reducer value inside of our cart reducer so that we clear out an item
regardless of its quantity.
When ever we hit this x button so of course we now know that we need to dispatch a new action that will
clear out that item based on an item that we pass in as the payload for this new action that we're trying
to write so let's actually do this.
Now we already know what we need to do from a redux standpoint.
We need to first make the new action type so inside of our car types.
Let's make a new one called Clear item from cart which is equal to the string value of clear item from
cart.
Now what we want to do with the actual action is we want to make a new action that dispatches the new
cleared him from cart that we just made.
So we will call it clear item from car as well which gets an item.
So it's a function that gets an item as a property just like our add item.
And in exactly similar way as our add item action creator we're going to set the type equal to our new
clear item from cart and set the payload equal to the item that we're trying to clear now that we have
this we need to actually update our reducer so that our reducer removes the appropriate item from the
array so inside of our cart reducer we're going to make a new case that will listen to our new action
so this will be our car action type stuff.
Clear item from cart and what it will return is going to be a new object where we spread everything
in our state but we also want to update our cart items so that now it will return a new array with out
any instance of that item that we're trying to clear away.
Now the code that we need to right here in our reducer is going to be a filter if you remember from
filter we're just going to call on our existing car items array that exists on our state right now and
we're going to filter it passing in the appropriate car.
Item and then what we'll say is that if the cart item I.D. does not match the action payload which we
know is the item we're trying to remove I.D. then I want you to keep it.
If that car item I.D. does match the items I.D. that we're trying to remove from our payload then I
want you to filter it out.
Now as you remember filter returns us back anything that yields true inside of the actual function as
the return of the function here what it's saying is that if the car items I.D. does not match the item
we're trying to filter then return true.
So we'll keep that item right because we want to keep any item where the idea is not the one that we're
trying to clear up.
So that's what filter does and it gives us back a new array with this.
We've made our clear item from cart.
We just need to now bind it to our checkout item component.
So what we're going to do is inside of our checkout item component we are going to now import interconnect
because we need to use we need to bind our actual new action to our component very similar to how we
did it with ADD item so we'll just import that in as clear item from cart from our redux folder cart
cart action then we need to make our map dispatch to props which is equal to this function that gets
dispatch from the redux store and then we will return our new clear item and with this clear item function
we are going to set it to pretty much what we had earlier with our ad item.
The only difference is that now we're using our new clear item for cart function.
So we'll make sure to dispatch clear item from cart passing in our item as you see this shape is very
similar to the code that we wrote inside of our collection item.
When we map dispatch our an item.
Function and then we just have to make sure to connect passing info and our map dispatch to props
wrapping our checkout.
Item.
So now we need the cart item.
So instead of destruction these values off here remember by doing this and destruction these values
this way one layer deep.
So we're pulling cart item off the props object and then pulling these values off of the cart item.
We actually don't have access to the car item property.
So what we need to do is we need to again do an explicit return in this function and just make sure
to set the concept of these values inside of the squiggly lines of our function definition and now we'll
have access to our cart item as well as our new clear item function that we're passing in.
So now on our Remove button we can do our on click where we create a new anonymous function that will
call our new clear item function that we're passing in as a prop and we'll pass the cart item in like
so and now we have our clear item working.
So this is very similar to our ad item functionality that we wrote a couple lessons ago except now the
main difference is that our reducer changes its functionality instead of doing our ad item to cart.
We're doing this new filter which returns us a new array with the appropriate item filtered out.
Now if we go back to our application we go back to our shop.
We add some items and let's say I wanted to get rid of brown cowboy if I hit the x.
We see that it got removed.
We see our clear item from car action being fired.
And of course we see our cart cart items array reflecting the new changes and just like that we've now
built in our clear item from cart feature that was actually pretty simple.
It's pretty much just the same pattern that we were used to from writing our ad item feature and you'll
see that much of redux is pretty much just this pattern that we've written twice now.
We mainly want to do something with our reducer passing in some specific object as a payload maybe not
even an object.
Maybe it's some property and what we do is we just want to update our reducer.
So we want to update our state values accordingly depending on what we're getting we'll actually see
this in bit more detail once we add in our arrows and we reuse our add item as well as make a new remove
item feature inside of our checkout item we'll do that in the next lesson.