Why do we want to use redux as we mentioned before redux is really really good at managing state especially
a large state so redux is a library that we would want to use if our apps get bigger and bigger and
bigger and they have larger and larger state.
Remember we want to use tools based on the problems of the self and we duck solves the problem of what
happens when react apps get really really big and using just this dot state just doesn't make sense
anymore.
It gets more and more complicated remember react is what we call a view layer.
It's really good at The View side but not necessarily at managing state.
So use redux when things get really really complicated.
The second point is useful for sharing data between containers and this is another thing with when projects
become large when they need to start sharing state between containers with react.
This is actually a little bit difficult and you have to move the state up one layer so that you have
a parent that can share state between the two.
But with redux this becomes really really easy as we're going to demonstrate in our coding section and
finally redux has predictable state management using the three principles.
Now what are the three principles these three principles and Redux are gonna really really make sense.
At the end but I want to still introduce them to you so that we're aware of them.
The first one is the idea of single source of truth and this is a fancy way of saying that we have one
single big object that describes the entire state of the app.
Remember this we had one massive state object that describes everything within our app.
So we have our single source of truth because react reacts based on whatever the state is.
We can just have one big object that describes how the app should look and react we'll take care of
it.
The second principle is the idea that state is read only and this encourages something called Image
ability which is not modifying the object and it prevents unexpected errors this way.
So the state object that we will create with redux will actually never get modified and instead we would
create a new state after each action is taken by the user and then finally the third principle is the
idea that changes are made only using pure functions something that we've talked about in my previous
course.
The idea that a pure function is something that receives an input and always returns an output that
is predictable.
If we enter the same end but a thousand times we expect that function to have the same output a thousand
times using these principles redux has some new words that we're going to introduce in our vocabulary
and we're gonna be comfortable with them by the end of this section.
The first one is action and action is something that a user does such as clicking on a button or a drop
down menu and what happens in redux is as soon as a user clicks on something a button and creates an
action.
It goes through something called a reducer and a reducer is simply a function.
A pure function that receives an input which is the action so the user just clicked on a button and
creates an output and this output is the state or the store as we call it in redux which is the entire
state of the app.
So as it goes through the function the store gets updated and react because it notices this state change
makes changes to the view.
Again these are wars that we're going to encounter as we start coding along.
Now why do this.
I mean can we just have an action and then an action happens and then we just make changes.
I mean that's how something like Jake we're used to work and yeah it looks more complicated doesn't
it.
Adding all these steps beforehand but as you can see above if you have tons of actions happening which
with modern apps that are very interactive.
This happens a lot where the users scroll action and then the clicks a button and then highlight something
and so on and so forth.
You see that the more and more actions we have the more changes we have to make and those changes might
trigger other actions which trigger other changes and so on and so forth.
And you can get pretty pretty complicated as you can see in this diagram.
With redux we make sure that all the actions go through one reducer everything flows through this function
and through this function it always because it's pure returns the same state based on the action and
updates the store and this store now which represents what our app should look like.
Makes changes so it kind of funnels all these actions into one reducer so that everything is predictable
and nice.
Again one of those things that's hard to really explain without encountering the problem first which
we'll get to now redux and I want to teach this just for historical purposes uses an architectural Pradhan
called Flux pattern architecture and software is used as a way to make sure that we're able to solve
problems in a logical sense and in an organized fashion in this flux pattern which inspired the library
redux.
Has this idea of having an action and then having a dispatcher that dispatches this action to the store
which is our state which updates the view and it's one way data flow everything flows one way if the
view gets updated we go back to the action and again goes to dispatcher that dispatches the change to
the store and then to the view and this was a pretty revolutionary idea because before that we had something
called MVC or model view controller and you may have heard of it it was quite quite popular the idea
with an MVC pattern is we have an action and that action is read by a controller.
So again another JavaScript file that looks for actions user clicks on a button and based on whatever
the controller says we update the model or the data.
In this case so we can think of it as state we change something in the model and then it updates the
view.
Now the problem with the MVC pattern is well this diagram over here we have the controller that changes
different pieces of the model.
And this model can change the view that can trigger a another change.
And that model can change another part of the view and so on and so forth.
And we have this thing that we saw before.
We have the craziness of actions and making changes all these arrows just criss crossing and not looking
very nice.
And although it might not be bad when your apps are smaller as your apps get bigger you want to do something
like this.
So it's logical and makes sense and that's what we want to do with architecture.
We want to architect our apps in ways that as they grow although we may add a few things in the end
everything is easier to reason about and understand so we have the flux pattern which enforces a unique
directional data flow we have the MVC pattern which could definitely be improved if you get anything
out of this video.
The one thing I want you to understand is the idea that redux at the end of the day is pretty much the
same as this DOD state and react with three ducks so we can replace this dot state and theoretically
remove all of this dot state from react and have it all happen inside of this redux library which again
we're going to do but one caveat you could technically have redux with the state but also still keep
a little bit of React state in a component redux doesn't replace completely the this dot state or this
dot set state and react.
You can still use them together but like I said before without having gone into any of the code of redux
this might look a little bit overwhelming and confusing.
I promise you things are going to make sense by the end.
Before I throw code onto the screen I want to make sure that you have some principles and concepts that
we're working from.