So now let's build in our quantity increase and decrease feature so looking at the final product what
we want to be able to do is have these arrows that are able to increase the quantity of an item or decrease
the item and we're able to do this because the right arrow fires are ad item action that we've already
created before.
But the also this new remove item action that's going to be very similar.
Now alternatively one thing we have to consider when building these features is what is the full functionality.
So one case might be what happens if we're on the last quantity and then we hit decrease again.
Well we see that actually removes the item.
So we have to consider that into the way that we build this feature because we want to be able to scope
out everything that we need before we start building it.
Now we know that we need to add in these arrows to our checkout item component and we also know that
we need at the very least one more new cart action for remove item so let's start building this out.
The first thing we have to do is add these arrows to our component so let's go into our code and let's
modify our checkout item component so the first thing we have to do is add the arrows in and they're
actually going to be using these Unicode eight windings just like the X that we have for a Remove button
except we'll use a left word and a right word facing arrow and they're gonna be in divs with the class
name of Arrow flips.
Gotta make sure to keep them open let's copy this and paste this down and the windowing code that we're
gonna use is going to start with Amber sand hashtag and it's 1 0 0 9 4 semicolon.
So this one is our left word facing arrow and now the right word facing one is just one number increased
so it's going to be Amber sand.
Hashtag 1 0 0 9 5 semicolon and now if we save we also need to wrap our quantity in a span and this
span will have the class name of value.
And the reason we want to add these actual elements is so that we can apply better styling to it because
right now if we look at our application we'll see that if we add an item that it's not styled yet it's
vertically aligned which we don't want.
So what we want to do inside of our style sheet for checkout item is change this quantity to have display
flex which will put them in that horizontal side by side alignment based on how much space there is.
Now inside of here we want our arrow class names to have a cursor of pointer so that the user can tell
that it's a clickable element and then for our value we want to margin 0 10 pixels so zero on the top
and bottom 10 pixels on the left and right and now if we check again we see that it looks how we want
it to.
Now let's actually find the functionality that we want to our left and right click.
Now we know that our right click already is using the ad item action that we already have.
So we don't need to build this one but the remove item one seems like it's kind of daunting because
not only does it have to decrease the quantity but we also have to consider how to remove it.
But we've already done that if you think about it with our remove action right.
We've done something very similar.
So our code much of it has already been something we've written before it's just the composition is
gonna be a little different but it'll be interesting because it's going to combine all of these concepts
that we've already been tackling and learning.
So let's go into our cart types to add a new action stream type called remove item
and then let's go to our action creators for our cart actions and let's make a new one called remove.
Action
remove item
and it's going to be cart action types dot remove item and the payload will still be the item.
Exactly like our add item.
Now what we want to do is modify our producer so inside of our cart reducer we are going to make another
case right underneath our add item for car action types.
Remove item and we're going to return an object spread in the state because we want all the properties
right that aren't changing but the ones that we do want to change is cart items and we're going to write
a new utility function that will return us the array with the modified cart item with the decreased
quantity or the removed item from our existing cart items.
If it was the last one so let's go to our cart utilize and write this function.
So let's think about what we need to do.
We need to first figure out if there's an existing cart item already inside of our car.
Items which we know there must be because we're decreasing it.
Right.
So we know there must already be one and then what we want to do need to check of the quantity is 1
so that we can remove it.
Otherwise decrease the quantity.
So it sounds like there's a lot but it's actually quite similar to the code that we've already written
so let's get started so we'll say remove item from cart is equal to this function so we know that we
need the card items because we've got to check the existing cart items to see if our cart item to remove
is inside of it.
Right.
We need that existing item.
So this code here is going to be very similar.
It's going to be cart item stuff find and we're gonna check just like our add item to cart if the cart
item I.D. is equal to our cart.
Item 2 removes I.D. Now if we have the existing card what we're gonna check is only if the quantity
is equal to 1.
So we're gonna say if the existing cart items quantity is equal to one then we want to filter it out
just like we did when we ran our clear item code right.
Just like this filter it's the exact same idea.
We just want to remove it and we want to keep all the ones where the cart items I.D. don't match the
one we're trying to remove because that's what filter needs to say return cart items to filter where
the ones of the cart item the I.D. does not match our car item to remove that I.D. because we want to
keep those ones right.
So just like before filter keeps the values where the function returns true.
So if the I.D. is not the one that we want to remove then we want to keep them.
If it does.
Right.
If it is then I want to remove that cart.
Item now.
Alternatively if the quantity is not 1 and we know there is the existing cart item because there must
be.
Right.
What we're going to return is we're going to say cart items
and very similar to this function it's gonna be cart item where we are going to just say cart item dot
I.D. is equal to cart item to remove dot I.D..
Right.
If it if it is the same one we want to decrease the quantity we're going to turn a new object spread
in the cart items.
Right.
All the properties except we want the quantity to go to cart item quantity
minus one
otherwise what we want is to return just the cart item and that's all there is to it.
If the existing items quantity at one remove it otherwise decrease the quantity.
Right and keep every other cart item the exact same because they don't need to be modified and now that
we have this code let's just bring this into our reducer
and we can just do state dog cart items and action dog payload.
And now we have a reducer setup.
We have our action creator.
Let's add this to our checkout item.
Now let's just bring an ad item and remove item and modify our map dispatch to dispatch them at item
goes to item dispatch ad item where the payload loops cannot type is our item and similarly remove item
for dispatch or remove item where the item is our payload.
Now let's D structure them in and bind them to the on click.
So on our leftward facing arrow we want our removed item with our car item and then on our right worth
facing Arab
we want add item with our cart item and now if we add some items we'll see that we're able to increase
on a click of the smaller era decrease and remove all our functionality as in and by combining everything
we've learned up until this point we've built a pretty robust feature.
So this is pretty cool.
We've managed to actually do everything that we need for this item toggling and it's just building upon
all the same code and ideas that we've already explored so far.
It was just a matter of putting it together and mentally figuring out what we needed to do in order
for our feature to not only decrease the quantity but also remove it from our cart items.
If that was the last quantity while some of these features look kind of complex at first glance if we
just tackle it one step at a time and think about what it is that we need to do.
We're able to accomplish and build them pretty easily.
Now let's commit our code
and let's just say added an item and remove item functionality to checkout item component
and get push.
OK now let's continue.