We have reached a point in the application where we have to start reconsidering how we manage state
now in this section.
I'm really excited because we're about to cover redux if you've looked at the react ecosystem at all.
You've heard this been spoken about almost extensively and constantly because it's such a huge and integral
part of not only react developments history but also it's a humungous part of how apps are built today
and how they have been built for the last two to three years now before we actually start writing any
redux code.
We have to understand some fundamental concepts of redux but also why we need a solution like redux.
So in order to understand why we need it the solution we have to understand the problems that it's aiming
to solve now in this lesson I'm going to try and explain to you where the problem comes from in our
existing app already so where it begins is let's look at our app component so anything related to when
our user that we just built and authenticated and stored in our database and then store in our state
is all kept on our app state inside of our top level app component if we wanted for example to pass
this current user into the header component as we already have.
We just pass it to the header.
But let's say inside of our header we had a cart component and that cart component for some reason needed
the current user.
So if we were to imagine that we had some car component nested in here that need a current user as well
we would be passing current user from our header which gets it from the app but if our header component
did not need the current user and only our cart component needed it but our car component was still
nested inside of our header component then we would have to drill that prop down from our app into our
header before finally passing it from our header into our cart this style of drilling props down from
components into their children is a bad pattern because the props in between those components in between
don't actually need that prop.
Only the child needs that prop and potentially the child of the child is the only one that needs that
prop.
So let's look at a diagram and see how this looks.
Let's say we have these squares that represent components.
And the further they go down is where they're nested.
Right.
So this component is a is a child of this component which is a child of this component which is a child
of this component before finally being a child of our app component so our app component stores the
state of the current user on its local component state.
If our header component had a car component inside as we just demonstrated that needs the current user
while we would be passing it from our app component to our header component.
Before I had a component finally passes it to our car component.
But what if our car component was also being used in a different section of the application.
Right.
And in that application it's even deeper nested.
So there's a page component some component and some other component before finally reaching the car
component.
We see that we would end up passing our current user down three to four components that all might not
even need the current user.
And in that sense this component suddenly now has to consider that it might get current user as a prop
even if that component gets use somewhere else and car component is not even a child of that component.
We have to write our code suddenly to be flexible and have these conditional prompts just because there's
a chance that car component is a child of one of its children.
We can see how that makes our code way less reusable and just in order to make it reusable.
We have to add these sudden conditional properties that makes it so that this parent has to be aware
of its children's component props without it really being necessary.
Now one way that you might be thinking that we could remedy this is what if we were to take this state
right and this component did mount all these all this code that gives our current user property or site
current user data to be stored on this component.
And what if we moved it into car component right.
Because car component needs current user.
So why don't we make it so the car components also listening for the current user right.
And then they store the state locally and then that would avoid this problem.
Well the issue with doing it that way is now that anywhere where we have that component that car component
it suddenly has its own state of the current user and that current user might be reused in App State
header car component and then this car component and other components not only are we repeating the
code which is bad but we're also having multiple states of the exact same current user data.